Wood mss., 1862-1923 LMC 2202
Lilly Library
Wood mss.
1862-1923
Lilly Library
Wood, Hiram, 1819-1878
Wood, Eugene Waldo, 1848-1925
LMC 2202
13 bound
1 folio
The Wood mss., 1862-1923, consist of the account books, deeds, etc. of Hiram Wood, 1819-1878, and his son Eugene Waldo Wood, 1848-1925.
Access Restrictions
This collection is open for research.
Many collections are housed offsite; retrieval requires advance notice. Please make an appointment a minimum of one week in advance of your visit.
Biographical Note
Hiram Wood was born on August 5, 1819 at Foster, Providence County, Rhode Island. After working from 1843- 1845 in Tyler's store in Foster he was station agent for several years at Central Village, Connecticut, being at the same time connected with his brothers Albert and Ira in the mercantile business. He was also station agent at Webster, Massachusetts, for a number of years. In March 1868 he moved to Greenfield, Indiana, where he engaged in selling coal, lumber, flour, and feed until his death on October 7, 1878.
Eugene Waldo Wood was born in Foster, Providence County, Rhode Island, on May 31, 1848. After his father's death in 1878 he carried on his coal, lumber, flour and feed business in Greenfield, Indiana, until about 1890 when he turned to farming in Greenfield. In 1902 he moved to Sudbury, Massachusetts, and subsequently lived in Swampscott and Beverly, Massachusetts. He died at Prides Crossing, Massachusetts, on January 12, 1925.
Scope and Content Note
The Wood mss., 1862-1923, consist of the account books, deeds, etc. of Hiram Wood, 1819-1878, and his son Eugene Waldo Wood, 1848-1925.
The Hiram Wood mss. and papers, 1862-1878, in the collection are mainly for his Greenfield, Indiana period. They include three ledgers of his flour mill, 1867- 1869, 1870-1875, and 1875-1878; a petty ledger of the flour mill, 1873-1878; a petty ledger of the coal and lumber business, 1877-1878; a description of his real estate, 1878; the partition of his estate, 1878; and two pictures of him.
The Eugene Waldo Wood mss., 1878-1923, in the collection include both his Indiana and Massachusetts periods. They consist of six cashbooks, May 22, 1882 to July 23, 1923; an account book, July 1, 1884, of his coal and lumber business in Greenfield, Indiana; accounts, 1878-1888 and 1879-1893, in Hiram Wood's petty ledgers for 1873-1878, and 1877-1878; business forms and a business card.
Acquisition Information
Gift: 1954, 1958.
Wood, Hiram W.; Wood, Eugene Waldo
- Wood, Hiram. Ledger of flour mill., 1867-1869 (Bound 11)
- Wood, Hiram. Ledger of flour mill., 1870-1875 (Bound 12)
- Wood, Hiram. Ledger of flour mill., 1875-1878 (Bound 13)
- 1873-1888, 1 vol.
  - Wood, Hiram. Petty ledger of flour mill, 1873-1878 (Bound 10)
  - Wood, Eugene Waldo. Farm and feed store accounts, 1878-1888 (Bound 10)
- 1877-1893, 1 vol.
  - Wood, Hiram. Petty ledger of coal and lumber business, 1877-1878 (Bound 3)
  - Wood, Eugene Waldo. Accounts, 1879-1893 (Bound 3)
- Wood, Eugene Waldo. Cashbook., 1882, May 22--1885, May 19 (Bound 9)
- 1884, July 1 (Bound 1)
- 1884, July 1 (Bound 8)
- Wood, Eugene Waldo. Cashbook., 1885, May 22--1895, May 30 (Bound 7)
- Wood, Eugene Waldo. Cashbook., 1895, June 20--1909, Aug. 30 (Bound 6)
- Wood, Eugene Waldo. Cashbook., 1909, Sept. 13--1912, April 8 (Bound 2)
- Wood, Eugene Waldo. Cashbook., 1912, April 22--1916, Aug. 14 (Bound 5)
- Wood, Eugene Waldo. Cashbook., 1916, Sept. 6--1923, July 23 (Bound 4)
- Photographs and papers (Foliobox 16)